

# **Orkhan ALIYEV**

Software Engineer

#### **Personal Summary**

Computer Engineer specializing in Computer Vision, Artificial Neural Networks, Web and Desktop Softwares. Experienced with a lot of stages of the development cycle for dynamic projects. Wellversed in numerous programming languages including Python, C++, C#. Strong background in project management.

#### **Education**

# Karadeniz Technical University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

## **Contact:**



#### Adress:

Baku, Azerbaijan



#### Email:

orxanaliyev19@gmail.com



## Linkedin:

@aliyeorkhan1



## Github:

@aliyevorkhan



#### HackerRank:

@aliyevorkhan



## Website:

www.orkh.tech

#### **Professional Skills**

#### **Coding Languages:**

Python, C++, C#, SQL

#### Frameworks/Systems:

OpenCV, YOLO, TensorFlow/Keras, PyTorch, Pandas, MXNet, Flask, FastAPI, Redis, RestAPIs, Linux, Do Git, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, MySQL

## Foreign Languages:

• English

#### **Projects**

#### **Work Projects:**

AYVOS Inc.

- FastAPI Video Downloader Service (Multi-threaded)
- Hand Detection
- Image Difference Based Anomaly Detection
- RTSP Anomaly Detection
- Time Lapse Motion Heatmap Analytics
- Dropped Object Detection
- Fire and Smoke Detection

#### Freelance

- · Product Statistics Dashboard
- Person Tracker

#### securKEY Inc.

- Remote Desktop App.
- Video Conference App.

#### Freelance

- Admin Panel
- · Sales Statistics Dashboard
- User Activity Dashboard

## **Individual Projects:**

- Yahoo Finance API
- Fastgre (PostgreSQL and FastAPI integration)
- Pose-Estimation API
- Optical Character Recognition API
- FaceFinder AI based Web App.
- Stock Management System
- Face Recognition Under Spoofing Attacks
- Emotion Recognition and Statistical Representation
- Face Recognition and Identification
- Age and Gender Recognizer
- · Artificial Neural Network Library
- Image Processing Library
- Internship Management System

#### **Career Summary**

## **Software Engineer**

AYVOS Inc.

Aug. 2020 to present

 Designs and creates new software solutions to solve pain points with Al and Computer Vision techniques

## **Software Engineer**

securKEY Inc.

Mar. 2020 to Jul. 2020

- Developed and implemented security based new products on R&D phase
- Improved previous versions of products
- Solved security based problems

#### **Freelancer**

Worked with 2 different companies in specified period:

Oct. 2019 to Feb. 2020

 Developed Dashboards, AI solutions with Flask, FastAPI, Google-Firebase, YOLO and etc.

# **Intern Engineer**

KTU Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Lab. Jun. 2019 to Aug. 2019

 Researched and developed new approaches for image calibration techniques

## Freelancer

Worked with 3 different companies in specified period:

Nov. 2018 to May. 2019

 Developed Dashboards, Admin Panels with Flask, FastAPI, SQLite3

## **Intern Engineer**

Cybernet LLC.

Jul. 2018 to Sep. 2018

 Developed Single Sign On OAuth System to access all products firm has

#### **Theses and Publications**

- Smart Entry System Against Face Spoofing (Thesis)
- Engineers of Future International Students
  Symposium 2020 (Publication)